<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>install postgres on Mobu&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>/tags/install-postgres/</link>
    <description>Recent content in install postgres on Mobu&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mubasser Kamal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 22:20:35 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/install-postgres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PostGIS - Installation</title>
      <link>/2020/01/24/postgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 22:20:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/24/postgis/</guid>
      <description>Installation   Update APT package list and upgrade system Prerequisite: PostgreSQL will need to be installed and configured beforehand.
sudo apt update sudo apt -y upgrade  -y switch basically means automatic yes to prompts; assume &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; as answer to all prompts and run non-interactively
   Add UbuntuGIS-unstable repository &amp;amp; update sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntugis/ppa sudo apt-get update   Install PostGIS sudo apt install postgis postgresql-12.1-postgis-3.0.0  replace the postgresql version with your own</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL - Management</title>
      <link>/2020/01/24/postgres_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 21:24:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/24/postgres_management/</guid>
      <description>Service management sudo service postgresql stop sudo service postgresql start sudo service postgresql restart Enter the database you created psql testdb Creating a table CREATE TABLE [IF NOT EXISTS] table_name ( column_name1 col_type (field_length) column_constraints, column_name2 col_type (field_length), column_name3 col_type (field_length) ); Listing information     Command Action     \l list all databases   \dt display all tables in current schema   \du list all users   \d list all the tables in the database   \d+ table_name retrieve detailed information about a table     Roles     Command Action     \du username list a username if present   create role rolename create a role with an existing username   create role rolename noinherit login password passsword; Create a role with username and password   set role test; change role for current session to test   grant role2 to role1; Allow test1 to set its role as role2     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL - Setup &amp; Installation</title>
      <link>/2020/01/24/postgres/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:59:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/24/postgres/</guid>
      <description>Installing PostgreSQL Prerequisite: Make sure to have Ubuntu set up first.
 Using apt package manager, install Postgres (it&#39;s in the default Ubuntu repo).  $ sudo apt update $ sudo apt install postgresql postgresql-contrib Postgres associates roles with a matching Unix/Linux system account. So let&#39;s Switch over to the postgres account on your server by typing:  $ sudo -i -u postgres  postgres: this user is the superuser for the PostgreSQL instance</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>